In the coming series of lessons,
在接下来的几节课
we'll go into detail about risk factors and alpha factors.
我们将详细介绍风险因子和 alpha 因子
So, what's the difference,
二者有何区别
and why do we make this distinction?
为何要这么区分？
First, let's start with how factors,
首先解释下因子有何相同之处
whether risk factors or alpha factors, are the same.
无论是风险因子还是 alpha 因子
The use of factors this is based on the assumption that stocks
使用因子的依据是我们认为
with similar characteristics may move up or down in similar ways.
具有相似特性的股票以相似的方式上涨或下跌
For example, stocks may exhibit
例如 如果股票来自同一行业
similar price movements if they are also within the same sector
具有相似的市值 位于同一国家/地区或具有相似的基本面
or are similar in market cap or based in the same country or have similar fundamentals.
那么它们的股价变化比较相似
Factors represent these common characteristics such as sector,
因子可以表示这些共同特性
market cap, or market return or the country or book-to-market ratio.
例如行业 市值 市场收益率 国家/地区或账面市值比
If we model the return of a stock as the sum of
如果我们用风险因子和 alpha 因子
the contributions from risk factors and alpha factors,
表示股票收益模型
then we notice that each of these factors,
那么我们发现每个因子
both alpha and risk factors,
包括 alpha 因子和风险因子
contribute to the stock return.
对股票收益率都有影响
In other words, each factor is adding a little bit to the movement of the stock price.
换句话说 每个因子都对股价的变化有点影响
However, in practice, risk factors and
但是 在实践中
alpha factors are used to accomplish different goals.
风险因子和 alpha 因子用于不同的目的
We want to use factors to help us learn something
我们希望通过因子
about the distribution of expected future returns.
了解预期未来收益率的分布
Factors could be predictive of the mean of the distribution of expected returns or not.
因子可能会预测预期收益分布的均值
They could also help to explain a significant amount of
还可能会解释
the variance of the return distribution or not.
收益分布的方差为何出现很大的变化
Factors that significantly help explain the variance of
能有效解释收益分布方差的因子
the return distribution are candidates for use as risk factors.
可以作为风险因子
We want to find a set of risk factors that explain much of the variance of a portfolio.
我们希望找到一组能解释投资组合方差的风险因子
The reason is so that we can adjust portfolio weights to
从而调整投资组合权重
reduce that variance that's caused by these risk factors.
并降低这些风险因子导致的方差
Reducing the movement of a portfolio that may be attributed to
我们控制投资组合风险的方式是
risk factors is how we control portfolio risk.
降低可能由风险因子导致的投资组合变化
One major risk factor is the market return from the capital asset pricing model.
一个重要风险因子是资本资产定价模型中的市场收益
We saw earlier how adjusting portfolio weights to make them dollar neutral also helps
我们之前提到 调整投资组合权重 使其保持美元中性
to make a portfolio less sensitive to overall market movement thereby controlling risk.
还有助于投资组合对总体市场变化不太敏感 从而控制风险
Factors that are significantly predictive of the mean of the return of
能够有效预测收益分布均值的因子
distribution are candidates for use as alpha factors.
可以作为 alpha 因子
We want to find alpha factors that are predictive of
我们希望寻找在使用风险模型中性化价格变动后
future price movements after we've neutralized price movements using a risk model.
能够预测未来价格变化的 alpha 因子
For example, if a factor signals that
例如 如果某个因子表明
the mean of the expected return distribution is greater than zero,
预期收益分布的均值大于零
then this signal may indicate that the stock return will be
那么这个信号可能表示股票收益
positive in the future which also means it's a signal to buy.
在未来为正 所以是买入信号
One example of a former alpha factor is the market cap of a stock.
例如 以前 股票市值也属于 alpha 因子
Small-cap stocks tend to have higher returns compared to large cap stocks.
小盘股的收益往往比大盘股的高
Factors that are neither useful in explaining the variance nor predictive or the mean
无法解释方差或预测收益分布均值的因子
of the return distribution would probably not be used as either alpha or risk factors.
一般不会用作 alpha 因子或风险因子
One example would be days when there are full moons.
例如满月日期
Even though a full moon may tell you when to
虽然满月可能预示着
expect werewolves or other magical creatures to appear,
将出现狼人或其他神奇动物
it probably wouldn't tell you much about which stocks to long or short.
但是恐怕不能告诉你要做多或做空哪些股票